I was trying to figure out what is my
meaning on this earth. I think in my
lowest moment, I looked around and I
found the Bitcoin community. I think it
saved my company and it gave me a
mission, right? It it made me excited to
get out of bed every day. It it it gave
me a reason to get up in the morning and
I felt like instead of retiring, right,
and just disappearing from history
forever, you know, Bitcoin kind of uh
gave me a reason to be and it really
motivated me. You're talking to a
maximalist here. I'm beyond I'm beyond
the investor. My It's not my skin is in
the game. I'm beyond that. My soul is in
the game. It's the only game in the
casino. We can all win. A lot of people
love you on the internet. What would you
say to them? Uh what I would say
[Music]
is very pleased to be joined today at
the DAS in New York by Michael Sailor,
executive chairman of strategy. I'm
David Lynn. Bonnie Chang. We actually
met at your party not too long ago. So,
we're collaborating because we met
through you. The 100k party brings a lot
of people together. Well, good things
come out of your party and good things
come out of Bitcoin. We'll be talking
about Bitcoin and your macro views
today. Take it away, Bonnie. Um, you
went to the crypto summit and you made
an orange tie joke.
I'm wearing my orange tie.
Any other takeaways? Um, well, I thought
the fact that we were at the White House
was the first takeaway because a year
previous the White House and the entire
administration was somewhere between at
war with the industry and um and
unsupportive. Um, so the fact that the
president of the United States would
host everybody in the entire industry at
the White House was an extraordinary
milestone. and it hasn't happened. You
know, when's the last time a new
industry was faded by the White House in
the last 50 years? The second is the
president signed the strategic Bitcoin
reserve the day before and that was also
unexpected.
The um the third thing that was
unexpected is
um the evening after that summit uh the
secretary of the treasury arranged for
the OC to give guidance reversing the
anti- bitcoin anti- crypto
uh guidelines that had been hampering
the banking industry. We didn't you know
we'd been hoping for that but the fact
that it came so quickly was very
auspicious. And then that night, David
Saxs, the cryptogar, went onto a podcast
and
uh volunteered that the United States
government views Bitcoin as immaculately
conceived, the only truly decentralized
crypto network or the only the only
commodity as asset without an issuer.
They saw it as a sound store of value.
They view it as digital gold.
they don't intend to sell any and
they're going to look for ways to
acquire more. And I thought that was
relevant because for four years um the
previous administration had no
utterances on this except through the
legal filings of the of Gary Gendler.
And Gendler in a very subtle backhanded
way suggested that he would grudgingly
allow Bitcoin to exist and nothing else.
And so he kind of said, well, it's a
commodity, but he had so lots of
reservations and he and he slowed down
the institutional adoption of Bitcoin as
as much as one could reasonably slow it
down. Whereas what you saw on Friday
night of that crypto summit was the
administration embracing the industry
and and suggesting that they were going
to aggressively put pro- crypto, pro-
Bitcoin regs in place, embracing this
thing as not only is it a digital
commodity, but it's maybe a better
digital commodity than gold, right? the
the White House didn't declare that they
are going to accelerate their gold
acquisitions one way or the other. So I
thought it was a major inflection point
for the industry in terms of the
legitimization about the industry but uh
Bitcoin was legitimized on that day or
in that in that 24-hour period from the
point that the president signed the
strategic Bitcoin reserve to the point
that David Sax said this is the digital
commodity recognized by the United
States government. That was a pretty
important day in the life of the entire
industry.
Um I think last year you were talking
about banks being allowed to hold
Bitcoin. That would be a huge step
forward now after the OC announcement.
What do you think is going to happen
this year?
Well, I did have a chance to speak with
the Secretary of Treasury at the White
House and he shared with all of us that
he wanted um wanted to make sure that
the banking system was able to embrace
digital assets and handle digital
assets. and they have a program of uh
progressively thoughtfully rolling back
anti- bitcoin rules and of course that
requires guidance from many different uh
federal agencies the OC the FDIC
treasury uh also the Federal Reserve has
some uh some influence on this uh they
were pretty definitive that they were
going to find every anti anti- uh
anti-crypto rule, all the anti- bitcoin
uh guidance and rules and they were
going to reverse them explicitly as soon
as they could in a programmatic fashion
almost like week by week stepping
through that. So I thought that was
profound. The other insight um Bonnie
that comes from that summit is that the
Secretary of Treasury shows up and was
so
invaged and you also saw the Secretary
of Commerce very engaged and you also
saw Kelly Laughofner the Secretary of
Small Business Administration very
engaged. So you had three cabinet
members extremely engaged in addition to
David Saxs the cryptos are and uh maybe
the most powerful financial
regulator in the
world certainly in the US government but
maybe in the world is the secretary of
treasury of the United States. So Scott
Bessant and Scott Bessant had been
viewed to be
progressive and innovative uh when he
was nominated for the role, but he
hadn't said very much on the topic of
digital assets leading up to that
summit. And so Bessant showed himself to
be very well-versed, very
progressive, very thoughtful,
uh, and deliberate and, uh, and
supportive, you know, and I think that
that exceeds everybody's expectations.
We we knew David Saxs would be
supportive and we knew the president was
supportive, but you could imagine an
administration where you have one or two
members of the cabinet that are
supportive, but other members of the
cabinet that are simply moderate and uh
they want to move forward in a
deliberate, thoughtful, careful fashion
and they would slow things down.
But what I saw at the White House was I
saw that that everybody is supportive,
everybody is deliberate. This
administration is moving faster with
innovative programs and decisive,
courageous
uh pro business, pro technology, pro-
innovation programs. It's moving faster
than any administration in my lifetime.
You have to go all the way back to
Thatcher and Reagan in the 80s to see uh
such pro- innovation uh pro- uh business
uh pro freedom type actors but even they
I don't think moved nearly as quickly
and decisively and they didn't have so
many intricate
topics. So I really think this is like a
once in 50 years could be once in a
hundred year type
event and um and Bessant's actions and
his words both before and uh and if you
look at the interviews that he's given
after this summit uh they're very clear.
He he went on the Laura Trump show
uh last Saturday night. It was a show
that I was on. and he was on uh David
Saxs was on, but he stood he stood there
on camera in front of the White House
and he said, "We're going to make the
United States, you know, the digital
asset leader in the world. Digital
assets are here to stay." And that's the
secretary of the Treasury. And if you
think about every utterance from
previous secretaries of the Treasury on
this topic, right, that's a hundred
times more powerful than than anyone in
a like position has ever contemplated or
uttered in the history of this industry.
We'll come back to policies on digital
assets in just a bit. But just speaking
of Bessant, in the current
administration, Trump just earlier today
made a comment that he said the Fed
should cut rates to ease the economy's
transition to tariffs. The president is
pushing for rates to be lower. On the
one hand, tariffs do not go well with
equities and risk assets. On the other
hand, if the Fed listens to the
president either directly or indirectly,
we could get more liquidity. How do
these competing forces impact Bitcoin?
Bitcoin is every macro trader's favorite
asset because they can trade it 24/7,
365. They can trade it anywhere in the
world. They can trade it with any amount
of leverage. and they can cross
collateralize it with any other
asset and they can talk about it with
legal impunity because it's commodity.
It's not a security. And so that that
makes it uh the most attractive of all
assets to trade on a
trend. If you think there's a missile
attack coming, you want to sell it. If
you think the missile attack didn't, you
know, was overblown and there's not
going to be a war, you want to buy it.
Um, I think when people are panicking,
they tend to want to do a leverage short
on Bitcoin. When interest rates and when
the perception is we're going to a a
riskon environment or a looser money
environment, they'll turn the other way.
So I do think that I I do think that
um interest rates coming in or the
expectation of of uh interest rates
coming in is very bullish for the asset.
Uh you know there'll be certain points
where you'll probably see it rip up
because of that. I think that this is a
pro
business deregulation, low regulation,
pro business, low tax, pro- innovation
administration, you know, in general and
everything they're doing. All of those
things will be good for Bitcoin over
time. I think deregulation is very good
and I think low interest rates are very
good. Just a quick followup to that.
There was a counterargument I've heard
from other crypto investors that a pro
business administration is actually
bearish for Bitcoin short-term because
the central bank does not need to ease
as much. Perhaps the recession could be
stalled by pro business policies and
liquidity flows would not have a
positive impact on Bitcoin because of
that. How do you respond to that? I
think there's a lot of double reverse
logic that takes place in the macro
trading environment. Like for example,
if you knew there was lots of inflation
over the long term, the number one thing
to hold is Bitcoin. But when people
print a big inflation number, Bitcoin
will trade down in the short term. But
people but but but the double reverse
logic is inflation is high therefore the
interest rates are going up therefore
money is getting slurped out therefore I
should find something to sell so I'll
sell Bitcoin and I and that's why I
would
say there there are basically two ways
to to think about Bitcoin actually
there's three views there's the trader
there's the investor and there's the
maximalist okay the trader says, "It's
an asset. I can get a handle on it. I
can 50x lever it long and short."
They're obsessing over whether or not
good news is coming cuz good news is bad
news and bad news is good news, right?
And then they want to make sure they're
the first one to get the bad news so
they can treat it as good news so they
can get out of the trade before the bad
news manifest or something like that.
And if you're one of those traders, you
know who you are and more power to you.
I'm not that guy. Then the investor view
is this is the dominant digital monetary
network in the world. It's going to go
up by a factor of 10 to 100 and I'm just
going to hold it like Apple, like
Facebook, like Google, like Microsoft.
I'm going to hold it like my big tech
monopoly for the next decade and it's
going to jerk around a bit and and I'm
going to buy it on dips.
Uh the maximalist view is this is uh
property rights for 8 billion people.
This is the greatest opportunity of the
21st century. This is economic
empowerment for every business, every
country, every family, every individual.
Right? I'm going to support it at all
times, every way I can forever. Okay?
And so you're talking to a maximalist
here. I'm beyond I'm beyond the
investor.
uh my you know my it's not my s skin is
in the game. I'm beyond that. My soul is
in the game. But I think that um Thomas
Lee he's he's done some good work and he
says that Bitcoin generates all of its
gains in like 10 days a year. Funstrap
Thomas Lee Funstrat Thomas Lee and uh
that just means that you know somewhere
like 98 97% of the time nothing is
happening and you're waiting for
something to happen and uh I I would
say every macro theory about if the bad
thing happens that's good and if the
good thing happens that's bad and if if
enough bad things happen that's really
good because then a bad thing will
happen which will be good for us in the
midterm.
I get it. It's all true, but I just
don't choose to play the game. My view
of this is that's a game for
professionals. And you know it's you
know Howard Marks he says the problem
with all these day traders is the stock
goes from 10 to 11 you know and the guy
bought it at 10 and sold at 11 and then
it goes from
22 to 23 and he bought it at 22 and sold
it at 23 and then it goes from 33 to 32
and he shorted it at 33 and he brags
that he made $3. But the problem with
the whole thing is if he just bought it
at 10, he would have made like 10x that
much money with no stress, no anxiety,
and no risk. And so I I tend to
think, look, Bitcoin's going to grind up
30 to 60% a year for the next 20 years,
and my long-term risk cost of capital is
like 29% for 20 years. That being the
case, rather than try to time the
market, it seems to me like a better
idea would be go mortgage your house for
30 years at 3% interest or 6% interest
and then make an investment for 30 years
that where you have 6% cost of capital
and get 30% return on the capital and
you're getting 24% boost. So, I I I
think it's much better to figure out how
you raise capital and lever the trade or
how you build a business that actually
uh cashes in on that volatility instead
of being the day trader trying to guess
the volatility because it it just seems
like, you know, it's a fool's errand for
the average person. I understand.
Um, in one of your interviews you said
when you learned about Bitcoin you
couldn't sleep because you were just
afraid somebody else would learn it and
they would buy it. You couldn't buy it
anymore. But now you are the main force.
I I would argue that the reason why
everybody's buying Bitcoin cuz you are
preaching for Bitcoin and everybody
believes you. Does that not make it
harder for you to accumulate more
Bitcoin?
Well, I think the uh what
the
the equity and the beauty of the network
is it gets exponentially harder to
acquire Bitcoin over time. And that's
what makes the network secure and
stable. And that's a good thing for all
of us.
Um Bitcoin has matured over four years
and that's a good thing. We we used to
have uh you know uh extremely highly
levered poorly capitalized companies
driving the market like the offshore
exchange like FTX and three arrows and
Teral Luna and the like and um the the
market has matured such that now you
have large pools of uh more permanent
capital like uh Black Rocks Capital,
IBIT or Fidelity or Wall Street And uh
that will create uh less
volatility, lower draw downs, but it
will drive the price up. And um on the
other hand, it's kind of like saying,
you know, your family came to Manhattan
in 1700 and you bought up a bunch of
land and then you went back to Europe
and you told everybody that Manhattan's
going to be the greatest seapport in
North America. And here we are in 1800,
Michael, and your family owns like 47
blocks of Manhattan. But the prices of
Manhattan real estate have gone up by a
factor of 20. Isn't it getting it harder
for you to do business in Manhattan? And
the answer is, well, the price is going
up, but there's a lot of other people
that are in Manhattan that do things
that we can't do. And I'd much rather
have other businesses and other other
pools of capital. Like on the day that
Apple and Microsoft and Google enter the
Bitcoin ecosystem, the price will go up.
But the risk will go down and and one of
the interesting things about
volatility is like if you look at the
risk in the space if you're if you have
something which is 10x over
collateralized by bitcoin and the
volatility is 60
um well there's a risk and one way to
drive down the risk is to increase the
collateral but the other way to drive
down the risk is decrease the
volatility.
So it turns out you're better off being
like three times over collateralized
with an asset with a 30
volt than 10 times over collateralized
with an asset that's a 70 volt. And so I
think that's what's happening now that
the industry is growing up. It's
becoming more secure. It will be
accepted by banks. it will I I'll leave
it at this thought, which
is when your bank tells you they'll buy
Bitcoin for you and they'll make it
really
easy and you can do it on the phone.
It'll cost you a million dollars
Bitcoin. And when your bank calls you on
the phone and says, you know, you really
ought to buy Bitcoin. It's a digital
monetary
alternative. And when they recommend it,
it'll cost you $10 million of Bitcoin.
And right now, no bank's going to
recommend it, and they're not going to
help you buy it, and you're going to
have to jump through hoops, and you're
going to feel really nervous about it,
but you'll get to buy it around 100,000
or a little bit less than 100,000 of
Bitcoin. And I think they're all three
the same riskreward proposition. And I
will I bought it at 10,000. I'm buying
it in billions billions of dollars of
quantity at a 100,000. I'll be buying it
at a million. I'll be buying it at 10
million. And if you're if you're back
here interviewing me when it's 10
million a coin and you're going to say,
"Michael, it all worked out, but you
know, Bitcoin's a thousand times more
expensive. And don't you feel bad that
you convinced all these people to buy
Bitcoin at 10 million a coin?" I'm going
to say, well, Bonnie, you know, the
entire ecosystem is much less risky now,
and it's still the best investment
option. I think it's still better than
buying the S&P index. It's still better
than buying a warehouse in Siberia. I'm
going to keep buying it. It's just like
buying Manhattan real estate in the year
2025 when your family started buying
Manhattan real estate in the year 1700.
Um, can you comment on Bmax?
Yeah. So, BMAX is an ETF that launched u
about a week ago and there's a whole one
of the great use cases of of Bitcoin is
uh to put it in the middle of a capital
structure of a publicly traded company
and if you have a publicly traded
company, it causes your equity to be
very
volatile. So, like my company's uh my
company's the most volatile equity out
of the S&P 500 universe. sometimes a
volatility of 90 to 100. Well, when the
volatility of a public company gets
above
45, you can sell convertible bonds
because convertible arbitrageers
uh actually are able to sell that
volatility or extract it and that pays
the cost of the interest. So,
convertible bonds make sense for
companies that have volatility.
But but if your use of proceeds of that
convertible bond is to build a building
or to invest in a long duration project,
it might take 3 to 5 years before you
know that the money that the investment
was profitable. So most companies that
issue convertible bonds only do one and
done. They issue a bond and then it's 5
years before they issue another one. And
that's because their investment cycle is
so slow. and it's very
heterogeneous and uh the source of their
volatility is normally uncertainty about
whether the company will be
successful. Most well-run companies,
they aspire to get rid of volatility.
For example, if you're a CFO, you would
brag, "We have no volatility on the
balance sheet. We can never lose any
money." And then if you have a P&L, you
want to sign your customers to 3 to
10year contracts with escalators every
year. Look at Microsoft. No volatility
on the balance sheet. Three-year
enterprise agreements that roll
over and the CFO is renegotiating one
12th of those agreements every quarter.
And so you never have more than 8% of
your revenue ever in play and you can
forecast out. So that's best practice of
a conventional company.
If a company capitalizes on
Bitcoin, you could sell a a billion
dollar convertible bond. You could put
the money to work in one week. You could
announce that it was profitable the next
week. So the investment cycle isn't 3
years. The investment cycle might be 3
days. Okay? Then you could go back to
the market. You could issue another
convertible bond. You would make the
same exact investment.
uh the benchmark of profitability is
whether you create Bitcoin per
share. You could say, well, what if the
market doesn't really care about Bitcoin
per share? Well, the equity investors in
a Bitcoin company care about Bitcoin per
share. They've self- selected. So, when
you're on the Bitcoin standard is a
public company, you can issue
convertible bonds because you're going
to have the volatility. You're going to
have a very fast investment cycle. it's
homogeneous and you can actually create
a set of metrics to describe whether it
was uh whether it was accretive or
dilutive. So my company pioneered that.
We actually became the biggest
convertible bond issuer in 2024. We're
the biggest convertible bond issuer this
year. We're so big that we're actually
getting to the point where we're
outgrowing the convertible bond market.
And so the shorts and the cynics say,
"Well, you can't keep doing that because
you've, you know, you've outgrown the
market." Well, and BMAX is the answer to
the question, how do you grow the
convertible bond market? The reason that
the convertible bond market is um is uh
is uh a stable set of capital is because
most of the people in it are convertible
arbitrageers and you have to be a
specialist. And so those bonds are sold
144A over the counter to specialists who
engage in convertible arbitrage. But in
fact, those bonds would be very useful
to someone that wanted to be a Bitcoin
investor because those bonds
historically up until now have
outperformed Bitcoin. So, if you wanted
to actually buy an a bond that performed
like Bitcoin, maybe you want Bitcoin
upside, but you want limited downside or
a different downside exposure, you would
buy a Bitcoin convertible bond, but you
can't because the bonds are only traded
to qualified institutional buyers. So,
uh, BMAX is is an ETF that is actually,
um, plugging an over-the-counter
institutional market into the general
public market. So, you could boil it
down as to say, well, now there's a way
for a retail investor to buy convertible
bond
exposure and uh, in Bitcoin back
converts. But you could also say it
makes it much much easier for even an
institutional investor because they
don't have to trade over-the-counter.
They're over-the-counter markets are are
dark. They're wide bid ass spreads.
They're very inefficient. They're very
illquid. And so BMAX is creating
liquidity,
uh, availability,
transparency, and a certain degree of
continuity.
And I think that as instruments like
that come out, right, I I would say the
most valuable ETFs, by the way, they're
ones that let a retail investor or a
diversified investor very quickly put 2%
of their portfolio into something like I
want 2% in gold in like 1 minute. I want
to own 2% of the real estate in New York
City. You know, you you need a REIT to
do that. I want 2% of Bitcoin, right? or
I want 2% of Bitcoin back bonds. If you
have an instrument like that, it's
differentiated. It It really is doing
more than stock picking. I I'm not just
buying three stocks in the ETF that you
could have bought. I'm literally
crossing the 144A barrier and I'm buying
an institution in a in an institutional
over-the-counter market to make
available to you on Robin Hood. And uh
so I'm excited about things like that. I
think it's going to grow the convertible
bond market. It's going to bring new
types of investors to the market. I
would say my company has expanded the
market because we have found in my
opinion one of the great use of proceeds
for convertible bonds. What are we
doing? We're building a digital building
in one week. How many we're going to
build? We're just going to keep building
them, right? I what if you could do a
hundred bond issues and build a hundred
digital buildings and just keep coming
back over and over again. That's good
for the investor. It's good for the
market. It's good for the issuer, right?
And and uh BMAX is is just part of
bringing that idea to the general
public. Are you able to talk about the
reasoning behind adding Mara and Riot?
Because Micros well strategy strategy
has a um cash flow as a software
business, but for Mara and Riot to have
cash flow, I assume they will have to
sell Bitcoin.
Yeah. Well, I I'm not the issuer. Um uh
and so that would be a good interview
for you to have with uh Greg King,
right? uh who does issue BMAX. Uh and I
would be speculating, but I but in
general I think uh that's it's probably
from a regulatory point of view a little
bit easier uh to issue an ETF that's a
that's a diversified portfolio or
distributed portfolio of bonds from
multiple issuers instead of all bonds
from a single issuer. And I think that
would give comfort uh to a lot of
mainstream investors that this is it's
not a single issuer strategy but rather
it's an industry strategy. And I think
right now you'll see many companies on
the Bitcoin standard issue uh
convertible bonds. They are. And then I
think you'll see many companies on the
Bitcoin standard, you know, buy Bitcoin
for their treasury. And so so BMAX is an
example of a company offering access to
that trend. But ONB O W NB is another
interesting ETF that was uh put out by
Bitwise which is basically owning
companies on the Bitcoin
standard, right? And and those those uh
operators they'll they will balance
their portfolio for all sorts of reasons
over time.
Well, one of your rules of Bitcoin, you
have 21 rules of Bitcoin, Michael, is
well, they're all really interesting,
but one that stuck out to me is Bitcoin
is powered by chaos. You made a
reference to a Swiss bank during World
War II, for example. What is this
current chaotic environment? What is the
chaos currently that will drive Bitcoin
to new highs? Well, there's um like a
100x more capital invested in the
securities, the equities and the fixed
income securities of
corporations. And so, if we look at the
chaos over the past few months, if
you're invested in a Mexican company
that ships products to the US, when the
tariffs change, that's an
anxietyinducing event. If you're
invested in a company that sells
products into Canada and Canada changes
their tariff, that's an anxietyinducing
event. This morning on CNBC, the story
with the breaking news was the EU is
considering uh placing material fines on
I think it was Apple and Google
targeting US-based big tech companies.
And you know, Apple's response is
regulations from the EU will prevent us
from serving our
customers. And the commentator
speculates that the fine could be 10% of
revenues. And if you're an equity
investor, that's got to give you
anxiety. So I I think the real key here
is wars create anxiety. They, you know,
wars are bad for business. Fires in LA
are bad for property. Hurricanes are bad
for business. Tariffs, by the way, the
end of wars are bad for business.
There's a whole set of investors that
are having anxiety because if the war
ends, their stock crashes. The war on CO
created a lot of stock, a lot of equity
crashes and crashes of all sorts of
assets, explosions of other assets. But
when the war in COVID ended, it was
really bad for the pharmaceutical
stocks. And so the creation of wars, the
sessation of wars, the possible the
possibility of tariffs, the possibility
of no tariffs, all of these things
create
anxiety. They devalue assets. And you
know, chaos is just a manifestation of
entropy. And the whole, you know, when I
was at MIT, you know, we had this
tongue-in-cheek uh joke about
thermodynamics. We said, "Here are the
three laws of
thermodynamics. You can't
win, you can't break
even, and you can't get out of the
game." That's the three laws of
thermodynamics. And that describes
entropy. It's like bad stuff's
happening. Your warehouse is rusting.
you know, the the highways got blockage
there. You know, the train the the plane
crashed, a storm hit. I have the perfect
business and then there's a hurricane
and I have to cancel the conference.
Okay. So, when will that end? That will
never
end. But what if I could actually get
out of the game, right? What if I
actually could create a business
where here here's a business where there
are no fires, there are no wars, there
are no tariffs, there are no there's no
product obsolescence, there are no
competitors, right? There's no property
tax. There's no rent control. There's no
expropriation. What if I could what if I
had a business that was not facing all
those risks? And and that's what pure
digital capital is. That's what Bitcoin
is.
But now what if I posit this? What if I
said all the money in the world is
facing all that risk and here's an
escape from all that risk and the only
reason they haven't bought it is they
didn't know about it or they didn't have
a channel to swap the risky thing for
the riskless thing. So, Bitcoin is
powered by chaos
because chaos will never go away. It's
always going to
devalue all of the traditional physical
and financial capital assets. And it's
going to be the driver that causes all
the smart money in the world to run to
sell their physical and financial assets
and to buy a digital asset. And so
really as as the world gets educated and
as regulators create
on-ramps, right, when your bank handles
Bitcoin, when when a big tech company
can wire a billion dollars to the bank
every week and buy Bitcoin, they'll just
be wiring a billion dollars and swapping
it out because it's easy and it's
rational. So that's really what you're
looking at. And that and that's why I'm
I think it's just a very elegant uh and
beautiful asset. Well, the name strategy
is also beautiful. Can I know the
rationale behind the name change from
micro strategy to strategy?
You know, if you look at uh lots of
companies and lots of great companies as
you grow uh less is more. You
know, Sting used to be known known as
Gordon Sumner, you know, and Apple used
to be Apple
computer, right? And uh and Amazon was
Amazon
books, right? And
uh Shakespeare probably had
a longer name. Oh, William. William
Shakespeare,
right? It
and Madonna had a last name
and Prince, right? So, a as as um you
grow then the question is are you are
you dragging baggage with you and uh
Micro Strategy made sense 30 years ago
in the era of Microsoft. We were a
strategic consulting firm that used
computers and we wanted to send the
message that we were a computer savvy
strategic consulting firm. But then
eventually everybody used computers and
then using computers isn't really that
special anymore and micro really seems
dimminimous given our ambition. uh and
and over time I heard I would say 35% of
the people would say so tell me what's
going on with micro
strategies so how are things with micro
strategies and uh if you think about it
whenever you come up with a compound
word that is not really in the English
language you're working against the core
genetic protocol of all human
beings how How many people have learned
English? Billions, right? How many how
many hours of your life do you sit in
classroom learning to speak proper
English? How to spell English words, how
to pronounce English words? A lot. So,
what's the perfect brand? The perfect
brand name would be an English word that
a billion people were taught to spell at
age six or nine that was defined for
them. If you're going to be successful
in life, you need a good strategy. You
need a business strategy, a financial
strategy, a family
strategy, you know, a career strategy, a
media
strategy, right? And when you fail, it's
because you had a bad
strategy. And and so what we've done is
we've taken a a word that billions of
people know, that they can spell, that
they understand,
And uh and as they say, you know, the
design is not complete until there is
nothing left to take
away, right? And and you see that Steve
Jobs epitomized that with the iPhone and
Apple and uh Elon Musk is famous for
saying the biggest mistake that
engineers make is they optimize a
process that shouldn't
exist. And uh we thought about it. He
said, "Why make people pronounce five
syllables and write so many extra
letters and misspell the thing?" And
well, if you meet 10,000 people, how do
you feel about correcting 4,000 people
because they made a mistake?
Or maybe you make it, how about this?
Make it make it impossible to make a
mistake, right? And and what we did is
we kind of made it impossible to make
the mistake and now and now we've just
made it easy. and uh and elegant. And so
that's that's really the thinking behind
our strategy. Beautiful. You had an
interesting fireside chat session. You
talked about superpowers and Bitcoin and
the need for Bitcoin to be adopted if a
country were to remain or become a
superpower. Now, let's expand on that.
So, going into the future, Michael, will
there be an arms race between
superpowers to adopt Bitcoin? in which
countries are next. Yeah. So, I think
that Bitcoin is critical because as I
said, it's digital energy and that makes
it a digital economic system. And if
it's a digital economic system, it means
that a billion AIs, a billion computers
can swap energy and swap capital uh
things of value with each other at the
speed which they can think frictionfree.
And when you think about what's going to
power the robots, what's going to power
the driving cars, if I want to release
an AI into cyerspace and have it live,
if I want my AI that represents my
interest to actually negotiate with
10,000 other uh AIs every second, it's
going to be on a digital energy network.
It can't be on a physical or a financial
network.
So with that as the as the fundamental
right I the company the countries that
will embrace this first will be the most
pro- innovation pro technology countries
the obvious one in the poll position is
the United States for two reasons
because the US is the most powerful
country in the
world and because uh the US has uh the
most enlightened leadership in the world
right
Um, over the past four years, I've met
with regulators everywhere else in the
world. I've I've talked to
politicians. If you talk to people in
Mexico, in South America, in the Middle
East, in Europe, in Asia, they're all
looking at whether or not they have
permission from the United States to do
this. And everyone everyone is afraid to
get out from underneath that permission
because they feel like they would be cut
off from the banking network of the
world. So no innovation generally takes
place outside of the US except by
extraordinarily brave gray market
actors. And you can do it but you can't
you can act in the gray market but
you'll never get more than 1/100th of
the capital. Right? So if you want the
entire industry to grow by a factor of
100, you have to do it with a legitimate
path. The actor with the legitimacy
right now is the United States. Um after
November 5th, what you got was a pro-
innovation, pro- digital assets
president. And and by the way, that's
that's important, but history is
littered with examples of candidates
that make promises on the campaign trail
and then after they get elected, they
slow roll it and they say, "Yeah, well,
we'll get to that, but in 2 years, in 3
years, and they appoint people or or
they promise you to get elected and then
they appoint cabinet members that
disagree with you and the c and they're
like, well, I would do it, but the
secretary of whatever doesn't want to do
it and or whatever it's more difficult.
So what's really profound here over the
past four months is you have a president
that that uh joined forces with the
crypto community and the Bitcoin
community. They supported him to be
elected. He supports them. He
appointed pro- innovation, pro- digital
assets executives at Treasury, at the
SEC, at the
CFTC. But even beyond that, you know,
Tulsi Gabbard, RFK, and Howard Lutnik,
and Kelly Lawer are all noninancial
uh cabinet members that are also
supportive. And then he created a quasi
cabinet position, and the cryptos are.
And so now you've got one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven,
eight, eight cabinet members that I can
name off the top of my head that are
moving forward. And then he proceeded
with with executive order number one,
executive order number two, Bitcoin
strategic reserve, and then uh to set
the tempo and he created the air cover
for all the cabinet members to act
decisively. And so if I had to put my
money on a country that's going to be
going to be the leader in digital
assets, you got to say the United
States. And the US has such incredible
uh gravitational pull that I wouldn't be
surprised if it draws lots of capital
from outside the US both human capital
and financial capital outside of the US
into the US and it has catalyzed the
game theory dynamic here because the US
is moving fast. If you're an ally of the
US or an enemy or a friendmy of the US,
it doesn't matter. you've got to look at
this and they're all going to be drawn
into the ecosystem. They really can't
afford to ignore it at this point. And
so I think that uh what you have is a
catalytic effect that's created a
Cambrian explosion in
innovation and digital
transformation, right? the digital
transformation of capital, securities,
commodities, tokens, ideas, and
currencies. All of those things are
about to go at a rate of 10x or 100x
faster than they were on November 4th. A
very short comment for people that are
watching and adore and love
you. A lot of people love you on the
internet. What would you say to them? to
the kids that look at you and be like, I
want to grow up being just like him.
Uh what I would say is is you know in
the middle of 2020 under the co
lockdowns I found myself you know
frustrated, dejected
and uh
and I was trying to figure
out what is my meaning on this earth.
Dejected by what exactly? by by all of
the turmoil in the economy by the you
know I'd worked in my company for 30
years and we're competing with Microsoft
and we couldn't grow and I thought after
30 years of hard work doing 100,000
things right every year you know is this
how it all ends you know and I and you
know I think in my lowest moment I
looked around and I found the Bitcoin
community and I found Bitcoin the
ideology which led me to the protocol
which led me to the asset which led me
to the
network and I think it saved my company
and it gave me a mission, right? It it
made me excited to get out of bed every
day. It it it gave me a reason to get up
in the morning and I felt like instead
of
retiring, right, and just disappearing
from history forever, you know, Bitcoin
kind of uh gave me a reason to be and it
really motivated me and uh the result
was great for my investors, great for my
employees, it was great for my mental
and physical health. And now everywhere
I go in the world I meet people and
they're very motivated and you know they
say well thank you for you know sharing
your thoughts because it helped me to
get more comfortable and what I say to
them is well thank you because because
really it's being on the team that
motivates you to work so hard is I I
really couldn't do it if I didn't have
the support of the community and I you
know I think that Bitcoin is the
greatest team in the world. It's like
being on a a member of a global sports
team. Like you're you're all in a fan
club. Imagine hundreds of millions of
people and they're all rooting for the
same team. But there's a twist.
There's hundreds of millions of people
that are fans, but we're all players.
Every single person in the on this team
is on the field playing every day. I'm
playing my position, but you know the
the crew mechanic in Italy on the flight
line is also playing, you know, and the
guy on the beach in Brazil is also
playing and people here at this
conference are playing. So, this is this
is a team where everybody's a fan, but
everybody's a player. Everybody's got
skin in the game. When we're losing,
we're all getting bruised. You know,
we're all getting beat up together. And
and it's like all of us are feeling the
pain. And when we're winning,
everybody's winning together. And I
think that that is such a beautiful
thing for the world that you get to join
a team, play a game together where the
rules are all rigged in your favor. And
as I said before, it's the only game in
the casino we can all win.
So, I feel great attracting people to
join the team. I like being on the team.
I like playing the game. And uh and
thank you for your support. We love
having you on this, Michael. It was
amazing being able to speak with you in
person. Great honor. Thank you for
joining us. Thank you. Thank you.